Raymond Thomson

917 SE 28th Ave | Portland OR, 97214 | 971.295.6644 | raymond.e.thomson@gmail.com

Profile _____

Accomplished professional with diverse work experience seeking entry level position with forward looking organization. Two years of experience in administrative and office settings. Excels at problem solving, analysis, teamwork and adaptation. Thrives on finding creative ways to collaborate with people, while continuing to learn and grow both personally and professionally.

Skills Summary _____

- Excellent Writer
- MS Office Proficient
- Attention to Detail
- Proactive Communicator Multi-Tasker
- Types 60 wpm
- Dependable and Efficient
- Highly Organized
- Critical Thinker

Professional Experience

Chart Compliance Specialist (Contract Position) • Quest Center for Integrative Health • Portland, OR

2012

- Audited medical charts to bring them in compliance with regulatory standards
- Analyzed office systems to determine performance gaps in document retrieval for medical charts
- Conferred with staff to determine workable solutions for deficient office systems
- Designed new systems to ensure prompt and accurate compliance of medical charts in the future

HIV/AIDS Community Health Advisor • United States Peace Corps • Malawi, Southeast Africa

2009-2011

- Initiated community development projects by proposing, writing and securing 3 grants totaling \$6400
- Administered construction of a lodging house at village health center for patients and caretakers
- Implemented program for the provision of electricity and furnishings for local youth center
- Organized and advised community members in founding of a village library
- Taught world history, life skills and English classes to 55 students at secondary school

Judicial Clerk • Multnomah County Circuit Court • Portland, OR

2008-2009

- Drafted court documents and managed courtrooms on a rotating basis
- Coordinated courtroom proceedings with attorneys and public
- Directed court staff and assisted judges to ensure accuracy and diligence in distribution of court information
- Analyzed laws and prepared legal briefs for judges

Front Desk Supervisor • Argonaut Hotel • San Francisco, CA

2003-2004

- Managed front desk of four-star hotel
- Ensured guest security as responsible party of hotel with capacity to host over 600 guests
- Operated and organized all aspects of office, coordinating with all hotel departments
- Trained new employees in company procedures and job duties

Education

Juris Doctor • University of Idaho College of Law • Moscow, ID

2004-2007

Bachelor of Science: Philosophy • University of Idaho • Moscow, ID

1998—2002

Volunteer Service

- **Columbia River Peace Corps Association Scheduling Coordinator and Board Member Portland, OR** 2012
- St. Andrew Legal Clinic Intake attorney at non-profit family law firm Portland, OR

2007-2008

Legal Aid Services of Oregon • Pro bono attorney, Domestic Violence Project • Portland, OR

2007